<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Alexander</title>
    <link>http://ericalexander.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Alexander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ericalexander.org&#34;&gt;Eric Alexander&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 08:49:53 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ericalexander.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can They Code?</title>
      <link>http://ericalexander.org/posts/can-they-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 08:49:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ericalexander.org/posts/can-they-code/</guid>
      <description>We have a coding skillset requirement for engineering candidates at The Trade Desk. It’s a requirement for everyone from our DBAs to our Information Security Engineers.
I can probably guess what you may be thinking. Let’s get some common arguments out of the way.
“Software Engineers should focus on writing code. Let me focus on my discipline”
“There’s a shortage of InfoSec candidates. Why further limit the talent pool?”
Both are valid arguments that are hard to disagree with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infosec Hierarchy of Needs</title>
      <link>http://ericalexander.org/posts/infosec-hierarchy-of-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 06:46:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ericalexander.org/posts/infosec-hierarchy-of-needs/</guid>
      <description>Ever pondered the natural order of reducing risk in InfoSec or the natural order of working towards compliance? It’s something I’ve been thinking about lately. Maybe it’s related to the recurring conversation my wife and I have on the topic of Maslow’s hierarchy of needs.
Maslow’s hierarchy helps us understand the essential nature of needs and why some needs are only achieved when we’ve built the right foundation by solving needs in lower tiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Blog Back Together</title>
      <link>http://ericalexander.org/posts/getting-the-blog-back-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 15:10:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ericalexander.org/posts/getting-the-blog-back-together/</guid>
      <description>I used to have a blog. My old blog content is probably still hiding somewhere on archive.org. The death of my last blog was the culmination of a fading interest in blogging and a desire to simplify by reducing the number of things that needed my attention and time. I eventually came to the realization that I wanted to do other things and maintaining a blog wasn’t one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>